Arvin Jude Alipio

Software Engineer

A result-oriented and self-driven Software Engineer who specializes in Full-Stack Web Development and Agile Project Management. A person who is constantly improving his knowledge by continuously learning and keeping up with the latest trends with regards to the field of Information Technology.



arvinalipio@gmail.com

+639255681548

Unit 329, 3/F Alfaro Place Condominium 146 LP Leviste St., Bgy. Bel-Air, Salcedo Village, Makati, Philippines

17 February, 1998 🎬

youtube.com/ArvinAlipio

linkedin.com/in/arvin-alipio-b06b78143 in

medium.com/@arvinalipio

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software EngineerCambridge University Press

03/2020 - Present

Makati, Philippines

Full Stack Web Developer / SAP Basis Administrator DXC Technology

DAC recimolog

12/2018 – 03/2020 Achievements/Tasks Taguig, Philippines

- Full Stack Web Development using PHP Laravel Framework, Node JS, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, and Javascript
- Spearheaded the development of the improved Knowledge Management System Site used by the company's employees
- Was able to setup the Web server from scratch
- Writes code that adheres to clean code principles
- Create project documentations and guide for project on-boarding purposes
- Leads a small team of developers, and reports directly to the manager with regards to project updates.
- Performs system analysis and design of proposed web applications that complies with stakeholder requirements.
- Incident Management, System and Database Administration of Windows and Linux servers running SAP applications.

System EngineerCommude Philippines

03/2018 - 12/2018

Makati, Philippines

Achievements/Tasks

- Back-end Web Development using PHP Laravel Framework, Javascript, NodeJS, ASP .NET MVC
- Design SQL and MySQL databases based on business model and requirements
- Facilitate daily standup meetings
- Mentor and train interns with regards to Back-end Web Development

System Engineer Intern Commude Philippines

10/2017 - 02/2018

Makati, Philippines

Achievements/Tasks

- Back-end Web Development using PHP Laravel Framework, Javascript, ASP .NET MVC
- Participate in team meetings
- Test and deploy developed web applications

SKILLS

PHP Laravel **Javascript** NodeJS ReactJS Java MochaJS Docker Kubernetes HTML5 **jQuery** CSS3 Bootstrap MySQL MongoDB **REST ASP.NET** Python **GIT TDD SCRUM** Clean Code **SAP Basis**

EDUCATION

TERTIARY: Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (BSCS) From Mapúa University

- Full Academic Scholarship Awardee (2nd and 3rd term, S.Y. 2015 - 2016) - Had an average grade of not less than 1.25 for the previous quarter
- Half Academic Scholarship Awardee (4th term, S.Y. 2015 -2016) - Had an average grade of not less than 1.75 for the previous quarter

SECONDARY: High School Class Salutatorian From Harvesters' Missions International School

CERTIFICATES

Advanced Professional Proficiency in English (Listening and Reading)

Scored 980/990 on the Test of English for International Communication (TOEIC). Top Score Level.

Advanced Working Proficiency in English (Speaking)

Scored 170/200 on the Test of English for International Communication (TOEIC). Top Score Level.

Advanced Working Proficiency in English (Writing)

Got a perfect score (200/200) on the Test of English for International Communication (TOEIC). Top Score Level.

AREAS OF INTERESTS

Fullstack Web development

Agile Project Management

Mobile and Game development

DevOps